In the year 845...
the Colossal and Armored Titans
suddenly appeared, destroying the wall,
along with the life we'd known.
Humanity abandoned Wall Maria,
losing twenty percent of its population
and a third of its territory,
to retreat within Wall Rose.
And in the year 850, in Trost...
Once again, humanity could
not stop a Titan invasion.
Eren Jaeger had been
devoured by a Titan,
but reappeared, emerging
from a mysterious Titan.
Response
The Battle for Trost (6)
I'll ask you once more!
What are you?!
A human!
I see...
Then don't hate me for this.
Marco...
I can't...
I can't fight the Titans anymore!
What happened?
My friends were eaten
right in front of me!
I saw them devoured,
and I didn't even feel sad or angry...
All I could think was,
"I'm so glad that it wasn't me!"
But...
Next time, it'll be me...
I realized something.
Essentially, our job
is to fight the Titans
until they eat us, isn't it?
I'd rather die right now than be eaten!
Stop it...
Get a hold of yourself!
You aren't the only one.
Everyone is struggling with that fear!
Look at Sasha!
Even after what happened,
she is still a proud soldier!
I have a terrible stomachache.
May I go join the wounded?
I can't do this anymore!
Stop it!
Stop!
I guess that gag order
was indeed necessary...
Just look at them now.
If they learn about Eren...
A cannon shot?
Why only one?
Look! Smoke!
From inside the wall!
What?
What's going on?
Did they break through the floodgate?
No way! That's the strongest part...
Someone just screwed up
and dropped a shell.
But why is there so much smoke?
It can't be... A Titan's steam?
Wait!
Hey...
What is going on here?
It's alive...
Captain Wellman!
J-Just look at it!
It's too dangerous to get close!
Maintain your position
and remain on high alert!
Maintain your position!
Have the gunners load another round!
What is this?
I remember hearing the cannon fire...
And then there was a horrible
sound, a shock wave, and heat...
Are we inside a huge skeleton—
Eren protected us.
That's all we need to know for now.
Flowers survived, only inside...?
Hey!
Are you guys okay?!
Eren!
What is this?
No idea...
But this thing will soon dissipate
like any other Titan corpse...
Let's get away from it!
Are they in shock, or just
waiting to see what we'll do?
The Garrison isn't doing
anything right now, but...
They'll attack again before long.
After showing them this, I doubt we'll
be able to talk our way out.
But I do remember one thing...
The basement.
The basement of my house.
Dad said that if I go there,
I'll learn everything.
This happened to me because of him, too.
If I go to the basement,
I'll probably learn what
the Titans really are.
Damn it!
Then why did he hide it?
Isn't that information
what thousands of Survey
Corps soldiers died for?
Isn't it humanity's last hope?
And he's been keeping it locked
in the basement of our house?
What the hell was he thinking?
Where the hell has he been
the past five years, anyway?
Eren.
Right now, we have other priorities.
Yeah.
The smoke's clearing.
When you see them, attack.
Let's end this here.
Don't move yet!
I'm getting out of here.
Where will you go? And how?
For now, I don't care where.
But from there, over the walls,
to the basement.
Once I become a Titan again.
Can you do that?
I don't know how I do it myself.
But I still think I can!
It's similar to the way you can't explain
how you move your own arm.
Back there,
my only thought was stopping that shell.
So that body had no other function and
rotted away after having served its purpose.
This time, I'll turn
into something stronger.
A 15-meter class, like the one
that tore apart those Titans.
Eren.
Your nose is bleeding.
You look pale, and your
breaths are ragged.
Your body is in bad shape!
How I feel doesn't matter.
I've come up with two options.
First, if you don't try to protect me,
at least they won't kill you.
Although I've already
caused you trouble.
I'm thinking of leaving here alone.
No...
I'll go, too—
Eren,
I'm coming with you.
No!
If I can't keep up, you don't
need to worry about me.
But I don't have to do what you say.
I've told you to stop all that!
I'm not your little brother,
and I'm not a child!
Information We Can Share So Far:
Yeast (1)
A special yeast made only within Wall Sina keeps
fodder, wheat, beans, and other items from spoiling
for a long time when placed in storerooms or tents.
Information We Can Share So Far:
Yeast (2)
By seeding storage caches with
this yeast along supply lanes,
humanity prepares to retake Wall Maria.
Captain, the next round
will be loaded soon.
Should we attack again?
Wait for my signal!
Yes, sir.
The Garrison's giving no indication of
moving to attack with their blades.
Mikasa's more sensitive than
a stray cat to those things.
Loading the next round will probably take
a minimum of another twenty seconds.
Before then, Eren will have
made his move and left...
Why would I remember these
things at a time like this?
Is it because this is it for us?
And at the end, I was
nothing more than a coward, after all...
They saved me over and over,
but I was never able to save them.
As a friend, how can I stand
on equal ground with them?
How could I say I'd go with them?
When even I'm not sure I can?
Now, the three of us
will probably never
be together again...
Eren, I...
Wait, Mikasa.
I said I've come up with two options.
Armin,
I'll let you decide.
Huh?
I know what I've just
said isn't that realistic.
The smartest thing to do
would be to stay with the troops
and use this ability strategically.
I know it's crazy...
But if you think you can convince
the Garrison I'm not a threat right now,
I will trust your judgment and follow your lead.
That's my second option.
If you say you can't, I'll do
what I described before.
You have fifteen seconds to decide.
Whether or not you can,
I'll respect your decision.
Eren...
Why would you entrust
me with this choice?
Whenever things get really bad,
you always know the right thing to do.
And I want to rely on you.
When have I...
There have been plenty of times.
Five years ago, if you
hadn't called Hannes,
Titans would have eaten Mikasa and me.
Was it all...
just in my head?
Only I thought that I was useless?
That I was just slowing them down?
These two never thought
that for a second!
Armin, we're out of time!
Looks like the next round is loaded.
We can fire any time.
These two are putting
their lives in my hands.
The two people I trust
most in the world...
What could be more convincing than that?
I will persuade them.
The two of you, avoid doing anything
that'd make them think you're a threat.
Ever since Eren became
a Titan and fought for us,
something has been bothering me.
I don't have it all clear in
my head, but I'll do this!
I'll figure it out while I speak!
Stop!
You've finally shown
your true self, monster!
I'll do it!
I'll give the signal!
He is not an enemy of humanity!
We are prepared to share
all the information we have!
I'm not interested in hearing
you plead for your lives!
How can I believe you, when he's
shown us all what he really is?
If you say he's not an
enemy, then prove it!
If you can't, I'll be forced
to eliminate the threat!
There is no need for proof!
That's right... We don't.
The question isn't what we think of him!
What did you say?
I'm told that many of you saw him!
Then you saw him fighting the Titans!
And you saw the Titans swarm him!
That means the Titans considered him
food, the same way they think of us!
That is the truth, no matter
what we may think or believe!
He's right...
A Titan as an ally?
That's impossible.
But if we could control a Titan...
Prepare to attack!
Don't be fooled by their clever lies!
The Titans' actions have always
been beyond our understanding!
It's possible they could
pretend to be human,
speak human languages,
and try to deceive us!
We can't let them get
away with anything else!
No...
He isn't even trying to think!
He's scared of thinking!
Eren... Mikasa!
I am a soldier!
I swore long ago to dedicate
my life to the revival of humanity!
If that pursuit were to cost
me my life, I would be glad!
If we use his Titan powers and
the forces we still have,
we could take back this town!
With my final breath before my death,
I shall wish for humanity's glory,
and try to persuade you
of his strategic value!
Captain Wellman, I believe
we should consider—
Shut up!
Their pleas are irrelevant.
They are traitors.
Anyone who violates the
rules must be eliminated.
That is my duty as a soldier!
Enough.
As big as you are, you've always been
as delicate as a newborn fawn.
Commander Pixis!
Do you not see his splendid salute?
I've just arrived, but messengers have
kept me abreast of the situation.
You go command the reinforcements.
I think we should listen to them...
Reports by the Survey Corps had said
the Titans would come from the south.
In fact, it was Zhiganshina District,
south of Wall Maria, that was attacked.
Thus, it was widely believed that
the district south of Wall Rose,
Trost, had the highest likelihood
of being the next target.
Trost District, Inner Gate
Dot Pixis...
He is the High Commander
of the entire southern region, including Trost.
The man with absolute authority over
the defense of humanity's most important region.
No luck, huh?
I wouldn't mind being eaten by a
really beautiful Titan woman.
And he is known to be a total eccentric.
What is the Commander thinking?
Allowing them up there unguarded,
when we don't know what they are...
I don't know.
The Commander's ideas are always
beyond normal people's comprehension.
Captain...
The squads are in formation.
Oh, excellent.
I see.
And if we reach this basement,
we'll understand everything?
Yes... Will you believe me?
As long as you, yourself,
lack absolute conviction,
I can't promise more than
that I'll keep it in mind.
But I do take pride in being able to
recognize the truth of what I see.
I'll guarantee your safety.
Trainee Arlert, was it?
Yes, sir!
Back there, you said we could use
the Titan's power to reclaim this city.
Did you really think so?
Or was it just a plea to save your life?
Well...
Both.
What I meant was to have
Eren become a Titan,
then move that boulder
to seal the destroyed gate.
But it was just an idea...
I thought I could get them to at least
at least consider using Eren's power
to find a way out of our predicament.
Of course, I wanted to survive!
You wanted to survive.
I can trust those words
more than any others.
Well, Trainee Jaeger?
Yes?
Can you seal that hole?
Well... Well...
I don't know.
I don't know much more than
everyone else here does.
So... whether I can do it or not,
I can't answer you for
sure when I don't know.
That's true.
I'm sorry.
I asked the wrong question.
Will you do it? Or won't you?
I'll do it.
I'll do it!
I don't know whether
I can seal the hole...
But I'll do it!
Although they had fled out of fear,
soldiers choose to stand
once more on the battlefield.
Eren decides to become everyone's hope.
Icon
The Battle for Trost (7)